It was an age of war.
Relying on his skill alone...
one man wandered the land.
A samurai.
This man
is not a wandering samurai of today.
I'm watching.
How can you sleep through
such a touching movie?
I was awake for the climax.
The kissing scene?
Isn't that actress beautiful?
Yeah.
Oh, look at the time.
Oh, do you have plans?
I have a dinner with the yoga instructors.
I told you yesterday.
-You did?
-Yes, I did.
Could you do
the laundry when you get home?
-Okay.
-See you later.
Well, what should I do now?
After retiring,
he lost his title as a corporate man
and the support of his company.
Takeshi Kasumi, 60 years old.
This story is about
a normal 60-year-old man,
who is helped by a masterless samurai...
eating freely without being held back.
A gourmet fantasy.
Welcome!
Come in! Welcome!
Not in the mood for Indian food.
Italian?
Pasta?
-Is this the place?
-Yeah.
THE WHITE-HAIRED KNIGHT
Yes, this is it.
Looks delicious.
I feel uncomfortable though.
Soba sounds good, too.
SOBA NOODLE SHOP
A drink at a soba shop sounds good...
but it's still missing something.
What's that?
Good restaurants are often
on the road less traveled.
Recently, my senses have gotten better.
MITSUMINE
YAKITORI RESTAURANT
YAKITORI MENU
The smokey aroma
of the sauce is irresistible.
I'm going to have a drink here.
All right.
Welcome.
-Have a seat at the counter.
-Okay.
Here's a hot towel.
What would you like?
A beer and...
SIDE DISH MENU
-...pork stomach.
-Okay.
One pork stomach.
Any skewers?
Oh, yes.
Your five most recommended skewers.
Okay. One moment, please.
Five skewers, chef's choice.
He's by himself, too.
DRINK MENU ITEMS
DAILY SPECIALS
Nice ambience.
FOOD MENU ITEMS
So many choices.
Here is your beer...
-and an appetizer.
-Thank you.
Here's the pork stomach.
Thank you.
Thank you for the meal.
Crunchy texture.
Well-balanced seasoning.
Delectable.
Now, I'm excited to try the skewers.
Here you go.
Breast, skin, heart, cartilage,
and shiitake.
Thank you.
First, shiitake mushrooms.
It needs a little more punch.
That's better.
When I was a child,
I'd watch my dad eat this...
and wonder what was so good about it.
But now I understand
why he liked it so much.
This is the chicken breast.
Delicious.
Now, the heart.
Its great texture is irresistible.
Lastly, chicken skin.
Grilled crispy on the outside
but soft and juicy on the inside.
You eat with such
great facial expressions.
Sorry. It's just so good.
No, you have nothing to apologize for.
A customer's smile is a chef's reward.
Am I right?
I guess.
Welcome!
Be sure to ask them.
Yes, I know.
One person, one drink. Okay?
We have to tell them beforehand.
Pardon?
Foreigners...
will have just two skewers
and that's it.
They'll say they don't want a drink.
Oh, really?
They just find us online.
They're a major inconvenience.
He shouldn't say that.
They've traveled so far to come here.
All right. I can do this.
How do I say...?
We'll make something for them.
How much can they eat?
-Eight skewers.
-Understood.
I'll ask them if they want
salt or sauce.
Sauce--
I decide how to season
the skewers at this restaurant.
My apologies.
And their drinks?
Drinks.
-Two beers, please.
-Okay, understood.
Eight skewers. Chef's choice!
Your English is excellent.
No, not at all!
The company I worked for had me study...
but I'm not very good.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Thank you.
Chef...
one fuwa skewer, please.
Okay.
Fuwa?
Yes, fuwa is pig's lung.
Oh, really?
Thank you.
Well, I'll have one fuwa skewer, too,
please.
All right.
Stop that!
It's annoying.
Could you, please...?
No worries.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
-Thanks.
-Thank you.
You're welcome. Please, take your time.
I don't need them to take their time.
He doesn't have to be so mean to them.
Here's your fuwa.
Thank you.
-Here's your fuwa.
-Thank you.
Hey there! What are you doing?!
To add pepper before even eating it,
ruins the flavor!
Hold on--
That's not how you're supposed
to eat yakitori.
It's fine on the skewer!
He's going too far.
You foreigners...
Eat your food and get out of here.
Me? I can't.
I can't.
-I'm sorry for the nuisance.
-No trouble.
You're the real nuisance here.
I'd like to tell him that.
Eat it! Eat!
-Just eat already!
-And I was just enjoying my meal.
No! Impossible.
Your transgression is unforgiveable.
-Let go of them.
-What?
You ask me to overlook
the foreigners' insolence?
Indeed.
I need not heed the words of a stray dog.
Your presence is an insult. Begone!
You will not release them?
No more!
Away with you!
You do not listen.
That's enough!
Risk not your life
over such trivial matters.
Frivolous matters?
This battle is mine to fight.
Understood.
He's all yours.
You are a fool!
Do not let society's rules bind you.
You must trust your... intuition.
Ready for your check?
Well, before that...
Pardon me.
With the added pepper,
this is quite delicious.
You mean to criticize my seasoning?
No, not at all.
Your pride as a yakitori chef is
quite admirable.
But is it not best to let the customers
enjoy their food as they wish?
Well, I wasn't trying to...
Being scolded on manners
and methods at a restaurant...
makes the food lose its appeal.
Thank you for the meal.
He's so cool.
Give them some beef stew or something.
Okay.
"When in Rome, do as the Romans do,"
is often said, but...
This is on the house.
you should be able to eat
however you want.
Don't be bound by society's rules.
You must trust your intuition.
Thank you for this meal.
Amazing.
-Thank you.
-Thank you for coming.
For a moment there,
I was worried.
That refined gentleman... was no samurai.
He was a knight.
I'll never age as gracefully as him.
I'm drunk.
Subtitle translation by
Jeffrey Hales